Guide to the New York State College of Home Economics records, 1875-1979
College of Home Economics records, 1875-1979
- Series I. Administration and Personnel
  - Non-Professional Staff
    - McCracken, Kermit King; McCredy, Mrs. Jeannette E.; McCusker; Mrs. Joan Louise; McDaniels, Mary A.; McFerren, Margaret G.; McGraw, Mayme L.; McIlroy, Annie; McSkimming, Isabelle (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - Medlin, Clara Cuthbertson; Merdes, Mrs. Norma Wardle; Merriman, Ruth J.; Merritt, Ruth Stacey; Messinger, Mrs. Constance N (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - Miller, Lido; Minor, Carol; Mirantz, Mrs. Arline C.; Morehouse, Beverly Lynch; Morrow, Anne; Moskowitz, Mrs. Blanche T.; Moulton, Priscilla; Mundy, Elbert; Murphy, Arthur W (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - Murphy, Mrs. Eleanor Curtis (Sturges) - includes photograph; Myers, Mrs. Joan; Nardi, Clara; Nedrow, E. Paul; Newman, Elsie M.; Newton, Naomi; Nichols, Morey (Box 8, Folder 37)
    - Nobles, Mrs. Betty; Nolan, Anna; Nulle, Rachel Worthen; Nurmi, Elizabeth; Oehrle, Paula; Olson, Ethel; Overacker, Mrs. George; Overacker, George B (Box 8, Folder 38)
    - Packard, Mrs. Elizabeth; Parker, George W (Box 8, Folder 39)
    - Parsons, Mrs. Elsa; Paul, Thelma M.; Pearson, Mrs. Dorothy; Peiser, Mrs. Edith - includes photograph (Box 8, Folder 40)
    - Perez, Mrs. Mary Harrison; Pendleton, Mrs. Ann B.; Perkins, Alice W (Box 8, Folder 41)
    - Phillips, Mrs. Dorothy E.; Pierson, Blanche E. Martin; Pope, Vieno Pertula; Pratt, Mrs. Marian; Presswitz, Mrs. Marqery S (Box 8, Folder 42)
    - Probert, Dorothy; Probert, Dorothy Ann; Pullan, Edythe; Randolph, Mabel; Rathbun, Mrs. Alberta (Box 8, Folder 43)
    - Reed, Lucille Coggshall; Reed, Madeline Church; Reese, Irene Dowe; Reisman, Mrs. Leorita; Reslet, Frances Williams (Mrs.); Reulein, Pauline Babcock (Box 8, Folder 44)
    - Rezelman, Reyer; Rhea, Mrs. Flavia Wagner; Richards (Box 8, Folder 45)
    - Mrs. Joyce; Roach, Jacqueline C.; Robson, Mina (Box 8)
    - Roe, Sara; Rogers, Ruth S. Tilley; Ronto, Rose C.; Root, Hazel C.; Roskelly, Mrs. Helen; Ross, Evelyn; Ross, Mrs. Grace; Rosser, Mrs. Annetta; Roth, Evelyn (Box 8, Folder 46)
    - Royce, Mary G.; Ruane, Mary Rita; Rundle, Eleanor J.; Russell, Claribel; Russo, Mrs. Erna B.; Ryan, Bernadine F.; Ryan, Mrs. Bessie Belle - includes photograph (Box 8, Folder 47)
    - Sabella, Mrs. Marjorie; Sailor, Mrs. Sara B.; Saltsman, Anna; Sampel, Ruth D.; Sampson, Mrs. Marie; Sandman, Mrs. E. M. - includes photograph; Schaffer, Amelia; Schmehl, Mrs. Elizabeth P.; Schmidt, Fatanitza Louise - includes photograph; Schmutz, Mrs. LaRue; Schoenfeld, Mrs. Edith Martin; Schubert, Mrs. Ruth D. (Box 8, Folder 48)
    - Scudamore, Margaret; Seeholzer, Dorothy; Shelley, Mrs. Charline L.; Sheppard, Lillian E.; Short, Mrs. Madeline (Box 8, Folder 49)
    - Sigler, Rita; Sinski, Anthony; Slater, Mildred; Smirlock, Mrs. Doris; Smith, Barbara; Smith, Hilda Agnes; Smith, Mrs. Katherine M.; Smithcovs, Mrs. Martha; Somers, Mrs. Beulah; Stanzinao, Mrs. Helen M (Box 8, Folder 50)
    - Stevens, Dorothy, B. (Buckley); Stewart, Marjorie, J.; St. John, Ruth N.; Stimson, Mary Bradley; Stockholm, Gladys; Stocking, Mrs. Harriet (Box 8, Folder 51)
    - Stoehr, Mrs. Aida; Storey, Mrs. Marian - includes photo graph; Storey, Mary; Stout, Mrs. J. C.: Strasburg, Mrs. Dorothy E.; Stritzinger, Gustave; Stritzinger, Mina (Box 8, Folder 52)
    - Stromberg, Mrs. Jean; Sturges, Sally Lou; Swanson, Mrs. Mildred; Swartley, Mrs. Elizabeth; Swartwood, Mrs. Lena; Sweatland, George; Swisher, Mrs. Marjorie; Sykes, Clara (Box 8, Folder 53)
    - Tack, Betty; Takce, Ethel - includes photograph; Tate, Mrs.; Taylor, Mrs. Louise; Tefft, Mrs. Jean; Thilly, Margaret; Thomas, Eleanor; Thomas, Ella Anderson; Thompson, Bertha (Mrs.) (Box 8, Folder 54)
    - Thorne, Dorothy L.; Tittle, Mrs. Marcia; Todd, Dorothy; Todd, Mrs. Emily B.; Tomidy, Veronica Lorayne; Tompkins, Mrs. Flossie; Treleaven, Nellie; Tucker, Mildred; Tudi, Lela; Turner, Mrs. Mildred Edith; Tyree, Helen Agnes (Box 8, Folder 55)
    - Underwood, Irene J.; Van Natta, Doris; Volze, Eleanor C., Wardwell, Mrs. Lorena; Watros, Glenn; Watros, Vida Steen burgh; Watt, Martha W.; Weibly, Janice Mae; Weil, Frances M.; Weinberger, Irene; Weissbecker, Alice J. (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Welch, Cora; Welch, Mrs. Doris; Welch, Sarah; Westbrook, Mrs. Edna; Westlake, Harriet; Wetherbee, Phyllis Jeanne; Whipple, Diane (Barkdoll); Whitaker, Louise; Whitcraft, Marie (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Whitford, Dora; Whitford, June; White, Annie M.; Wilcox, Barbara A.; Wilhelm, Bernice Louise - includes photograph; Wilkinson, Helen; Wilkinson, Mary - includes photograph; Wilkinson, Virginia Ruth; Williams, Barbara (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Williams, Frances; Williams, Margery E. Ufford; Williamson, Edith Getman; Wilmot, Thomas; Wilson, Annabeth; Wolff, Helene C.; Wolff, Martha L.; Wood, Rachel (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Woodruff, Jeanette; Woods, Mrs. Mary Ellen; Woods, Shirley M.D.; Wooley, Hope; Wright, Mrs. Lucille; Wyman, Mrs. Florence - includes photograph; Yager, Joseph; Zapf, Florence M (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Employment of students at College to 1921 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Employment of students, alumni, non-students; reference and recommendation to 1921 (Box 9, Folder 7-13)
  - College Faculty and Staff
    - Staff correspondence: individual household, industrial and personal problems, to 1921 (Box 9, Folder 14-20)
    - Staff Civil Service Report 1930-1931 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Study of Faculty Ranks 1944, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Study of Degrees held by Faculty- 1-947 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Staff attendance at professional and scientific meetings, 1938-1939, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - School visiting by College faculty members 1938-1939 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Home visiting by staff members 1938-1942 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Data on faculty and staff (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Stenographic and Clerical Services
    - Stenographic service studies, 1937, 1939 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Stenographic service 1943-1944, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Mimeograph and multilith reports, 1940-1947 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Committees, Lists of (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - Standing Committees of the College 1927-1946 (Box 9, Folder 32-33)
    - Spafford Study 1937-1938 - Foods and Nutrition (Box 9, Folder 34-41)
    - Spafford Study - Household Art (Box 9, Folder 42)
    - Spafford Study - Textiles and Clothing (Box 9, Folder 43)
    - Spafford Study - Home Economics Education (Box 9, Folder 44)
    - Spafford Study - General (Box 9, Folder 45)
    - Spafford Study - Economics of the Household (Box 9, Folder 46)
    - Discussion group on General Education, 1952 (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - Evaluations of the College
    - Study of undergraduate teaching and checklist on other work for 1939-1940 (Box 9, Folder 48-49)
    - Memorandum on Certain Aspects of Administration in Cornell University, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 50)
    - Legal matters - Legislation: correspondence to 1921 (Box 9, Folder 51)
    - Federal laws - Smith-Lever Act - 1919 (Box 9, Folder 52)
    - Federal laws - Relation of federal cooperative extension employees to agricultural organizations (Box 9, Folder 53)
    - Federal laws - Capper-Ketcham Act - 1935 (Box 9, Folder 54)
    - Federal laws - Hope-Flannagan Bill - 1946 (Box 9, Folder 55)
    - State laws - Laws of New York State concerning Extension (Box 9, Folder 56)
    - State laws - College of Home Economics legislation of New York State Senate & Assembly, 1928 (Box 9, Folder 57)
    - State laws - Amendments to New York Vehicle and Traffic Law, 1949 (Box 9, Folder 58)
    - Local laws - legal problems of the department to 1921 (Box 9, Folder 59)
    - Miscellaneous administrative materials - administrative calendar of College (Box 9, Folder 60-61)
    - Miscellaneous administrative materials - college objectives, preliminary work-1932-1942 (Box 9, Folder 62)
    - Financial matters - Budgets 1912-1935 (Box 9, Folder 63-66)
    - Financial matters - Budgets 1912-1935 (Box 10, Folder 1-6)
    - Financial matters - Budgets 1935-1952 publications (Box 10, Folder 7-10)
    - Revised budqet 1945-1946 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Budgets 1949-1954 (Box 10, Folder 12-13)
    - Miscellaneous budgetary matters (Box 10, Folder 14-15)
    - Emergency budget 1941-1943 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Transfer of bookkeeping to Roberts Business office July 1943 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Budget - Acceleration (Box 10, Folder 18-19)
    - Budget - Bonuses (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Special state defense funds (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Miscellaneous financial & budgetary materials 1949-1959 (Box 10, Folder 22-26)
    - Research budget information 1949-1959 (Box 10, Folder 27-31)
  - Records of the College of Home Economics Placement Office
    - College Alumni/Personnel records, c. 1920's-1940's (Box 60-63)
    - Field Trips 1951-1957 (Box 69, Folder 14)
    - Elementary Certification - Cornell 1950's and 1960's (Box 69, Folder 15)
    - Secondary Certification - 1960's (Box 69, Folder 16)
    - Home Economic Students Employed Part-Time at College 1948-1958, 1961-1966 (Box 69, Folder 17)
    - Beginning Jobs - Vocational Information, 1950's and 1960's (Box 69, Folder 18)
    - Alumni Lists 1950's and 1960's (Box 69, Folder 19)
    - Brochure 1965 (Box 69, Folder 20)
    - Brochure 1963 (Box 69, Folder 21)
    - Brochure 1968- Alumni 1955-1957, 1960's (Box 69, Folder 22)
    - "This Job is Yours" - Publication put out by the Placement Office - 1946, 1948, 1952, 1960 (Box 69, Folder 23)
    - Letter from Esther Stocks to Alumnae - October 1953 (Box 69, Folder 24)
  - College Reports
    - The Department of Home Economics Education, by Margaret Hutchins - 1946-1958 (Box 59, Folder 20)
    - Ad Hoc Committee Recommendations on College Study Report and Faculty discussion - 1967 (Box 79, Folder 1)
    - Memoranda concerning Dept. of Textiles and Clothing & Organizational Committee - 1967 (Box 79, Folder 2)
    - Reactions to Report - 1966-1967 (Box 79, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence concerning President's Committee1965-1968 (Box 79, Folder 4)
    - Response to College Study Report, Ad Hoc Committees - 1967-1968 (Box 79, Folder 5)
    - Dept. of Home Economics Education, Reports 1958-1968 (Box 79, Folder 6)
    - Recommendations of an Ad Hoc Committee on the Status of Textiles and Clothing in a Reorganized College - October 22, 1968 (Box 79, Folder 7)
    - Organization of the College - Various Perspectives 1969 (Box 79, Folder 8)
    - Dean Knapp's Remarks and Memoranda, Reports,1968,1969,1972 (Box 79, Folder 9)
    - Community Service Education - HSS - late 1970'searly 1980's (Box 79, Folder 10)
    - College of Human Ecology - Memoranda, Reports 1970's (Box 79, Folder 11)
    - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1959-1968 (Box 80)
    - Department Heads Meeting Minutes, 1962-1966 (Box 80)
    - Faculty Meeting Minutes 1925-1943 (Box 81)
    - Department Heads Meeting Minutes, 1944-1962; 1966-1969 (Box 81)
    - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1943-1959 (Box 82)
    - Academic Services Committee, 1969-1973,Committee on Academic Status 1974-1976 (Box 85, Folder 1)
    - Academic Standing Faculty Committee - Annual Reports - 1946-1961,1963-1973' (Box 85, Folder 2)
    - Admissions - Annual Reports - 1947-1963 (Box 85, Folder 3)
    - Admissions - Annual Reports - 1965-1969 (Box 85, Folder 4)
    - Admissions - Annual Reports - 1969-1976 (Box 85, Folder 5)
    - Admissions Philosophy, Policies and Procedures of the Faculty Committee on Admissions 1964, 1967 (Box 85, Folder 6)
    - Attrition - Reports - 1939-1950, 1939-1955, 1966-1973 (Box 85, Folder 7)
    - Certification of Home Economics Teachers - 1958-1968 Proposed Program for Training PreKindergarten & KindergartenTeachers - 1968 (Box 85, Folder 8)
    - Communications - Publications Committee - Minutes & AnnualReports - 1950's & 1960's (Box 85, Folder 9)
    - Diversity - 1972-1973 (Box 85, Folder 10)
    - Extension Studies Committee - 1947-1950 (Box 85, Folder 11)
    - Graduate Education Committee - Annual Reports - 1969-1970, 1972-1973 Graduate Fellowship Committee - Annual Reports - 1975-1977 (Box 85, Folder 12)
    - Grants Committee - Annual Report - 1974-1976 (Box 85, Folder 13)
    - Mann Library Committee - Reports - 1947-1966 (Box 85, Folder 14)
    - 15 Nominations and Elections - Reports - 1948-1968 (Box 85, Folder 15)
    - Research Committee Reports - 1954-1973 (Box 86, Folder 1)
    - Student Faculty Committee - Reports - 1949-1969 (Box 86, Folder 4)
  - Study Concerning Change from Home Economics to Human Ecology, Refer to faculty meeting minutes from 1967 for discussions concerning the Final Report of the President's Committee to Study the College of Home Economics. (Pages 4484-4547 and 4666-4707 in the bound issues of the Faculty Minutes.); For more records concerning the Reorganization of the College of Home Economics, see Henry Riccluti's collection, #23-13-2551.; A copy of the final report of the President's Committee to Study the College of Home Economics, December 1966, can be found in collection #23-13-2551, box 1, folders 1-7
    - Sex Discrimination Case - Cornell vs. 5 woman professors - late 1970's (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - Sample Research Proposals - Community Service Education - Sara Blackwell (Box 78, Folder 2)
    - President's Committee to Study the College of Home Economics - Minutes, Memoranda, Correspondence - 1961-1965 (Box 78, Folder 3)
    - President's Committee to Study the College of Horne Economics - Memoranda, Goals, Proposals, correspondence, Minutes - 1961-1965 (Box 78, Folder 4)
    - President's Committee to Study the College of Home Economics - Minutes, Memoranda - 1965 (Box 78, Folder 5)
    - President's Committee to Study the College of Home Economics - External Consultants - 1966 (Box 78, Folder 6)
    - President's Committee to Study the College of Home Economics - Minutes, Reports - 1966 (Box 78, Folder 7)
    - President's Committee to Study the College of Home Economics - Progress Reports, Memoranda Reports to the Committee by people outside of Cornell, Minutes - 1966 (Box 78, Folder 8)
    - President's Committee to Study the College of Home Economics - Memoranda, Minutes - 1966 (Box 78, Folder 9-10)
    - President's Committee to Study the College of Home Economics - Reports, Memoranda, Discussion of final report - 1966 (Box 78, Folder 11)
    - Memoranda, Correspondence, Committee Reports, 1966-May 1967 (Box 78, Folder 12)
    - Final Report of the Preident's Committee to Study the College of Home Economics, 1966-December (Box 78, Folder 13)
- Series II. Cooperation of the College with Governmental, Educational, and Private Organizations, 1916-1959
  - Government, National, New York State
    - Government Groups - National - Land Grant College Association 1922-1932 (Box 10, Folder 32-36)
    - Government Groups - National - Land Grant College Association 1933-1940 (Box 10, Folder 37-40)
    - Government Groups - National - Land Grant College Association 1941-1943 (Box 10, Folder 41)
    - Government Groups - National - Land Grant College Association Nutrition Bill 1943-1945 (Box 10, Folder 42-43)
    - Government Groups - Land Grant - Home Economics Division (Historical) (Box 10, Folder 44)
    - Research Advisory Committee - Land Grant - (next meeting) (Box 10, Folder 45)
    - National Council of Parent Education - 1926-1929 (Box 10, Folder 46-47)
    - National Council of Parent Education - 1930-1931 (Box 10, Folder 48-51)
    - National Council of Parent Education - 1932-1935 (Box 11, Folder 1-5)
    - National Council of Youth Administration - 1935-1936 (Box 11, Folder 6-7)
    - National Council of Youth Administration - 1937-1940 (Box 11, Folder 8-12)
    - U.S.D.A. - policies 1918, 1923 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - U.S.D.A. - correspondence to 1921 (Box 11, Folder 14-15)
    - U.S.D.A. - Bureau of Home Economics Dietary Studies 1926 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - U.S.D.A. - Bureau of Home Economics 1931 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Origin of Bureau of Home Economics 1923 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - U.S. Department of Education - Federal Board of Vocational Education - 1926-1927 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - U.S. Department of Labor - correspondence to 1921 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - U.S. War Department Service - 1949 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - W.P.A. - Rural Rehabilitation 1934; Rural Settlement 1936 (Box 11, Folder 22-23)
    - Miscellaneous U.S. government groups - correspondence to 1921 (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Desmond Joint Legislative Committee on Nutrition, 1943-1946 (Box 11, Folder 25-26)
    - New York State Department of Agriculture, correspondence to 1921 (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - New York State Agricultural Advisory Commission: Martha Van Rensselaer (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - New York State Advisory Committee: Flora Rose, 1930-1934 (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - Farmers' Institutes (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - Farmers' Institute - Women's Institutes (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - Farmers' Institute - Women's - clippings (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - New York State Council of Rural Women - 1943 (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - New York State Department of Education - correspondence to 1921 (Box 11, Folder 34-35)
    - New York State Department of Education - Bureau of Home Economics Education 1941-1943 (Box 11, Folder 36-37)
    - New York State Department of Education - Bureau of Home Economics Education - 1922-1938 (Box 11, Folder 38-44)
    - New York State Department of Education - Bureau of Home Economics Education - 1944-1946 (Box 11, Folder 45-46)
    - New York State Department of Education - general - 1941-1946 (Box 11, Folder 47-49)
    - New York State Commissioner of Education Graves - correspondence with Martha Van Rensselaer - 1930 (Box 11, Folder 50)
    - New York State Department of Education Child Guidance - 1930-1932 (Box 11, Folder 51-52)
    - New York State Department of Education Home Report - 1934-1937 (Box 11, Folder 53)
    - New York State Flood Relief Program 1935 (Box 11, Folder 54)
    - New York State Food Commissioner (Box 11, Folder 55)
    - New York State Food Supply Commission - 1917 (Box 12, Folder 1-3)
    - New York State Nutrition Committee 1937-1949 (Box 12, Folder 4-7)
    - New York State Department~ of Health - correspondence to 1921 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - New York State Department of Labor - Children's Bureau 1937-1938 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - New York State Joint Legislative Economy Committee August 1942 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - New York State Joint Legislative Committee on Imitation Milk Products and Problems, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - New York State departments - correspondence to 1921 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Government Groups - Local
    - Cooperative Program between College and Nassau County, 1937-1938 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Tompkins County Development Association 1935-1937 (Box 12, Folder 14-15)
  - Private Groups
    - Associated Country Women of the World - 1936 (Box 12, Folder 16-18)
    - Associated Country Women of the World - 1940 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Private Groups - International
    - Agricultural missions Foundation - 1931-1945 (Box 12, Folder 20-22)
    - Miscellaneous international organizations - correspondence to 1921 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Private Groups National
    - American Country Life Association 1931 (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - American Home Economics Association correspondence to 1921 (Box 12, Folder 25-29)
    - American Home Economics Association Lake Placid Conference - correspondence to 1921 (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - American Home Economics Association 1916-30 (Box 12, Folder 31-34)
    - American Home Economics Association 1932 (Box 12, Folder 35)
    - American Home Economics Association 1930-1940 (Box 12, Folder 36-39)
    - American Home Economics Association 1940-1946 (Box 12, Folder 40-43)
    - American Red Cross - correspondence to 1921 (Box 12, Folder 44)
    - Association for Childhood Education - 1930 (Box 12, Folder 45)
    - Better Homes in America Organization 1922-1935 (Box 12, Folder 46)
    - Child Health organization of America (Box 12, Folder 47)
    - Foods Facts Foundation 1957 (Box 12, Folder 48)
    - League of Women Voters 1927-1930 (Box 12, Folder 49)
    - League of Women Voters - correspondence to 1921 (Box 12, Folder 50)
    - Mothers' Assembly - correspondence to 1921 (Box 12, Folder 51-52)
    - National Country Life Association - correspondence to 1921 (Box 12, Folder 53)
    - Girl Scouts (Box 12, Folder 54-55)
    - General Federation of Women's Clubs - correspondence to 1921 (Box 12, Folder 56-58)
    - Grange - correspondence to 1921 (Box 12, Folder 59)
    - Women's National Farm and Garden Association 1931-1936 (Box 13, Folder 4-Jan)
    - W.C.T.U. - correspondence to 1921 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Y.W.C.H. - correspondence to 1921 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - National organizations - correspondence to 1921 (Box 13, Folder 7-9)
  - Private Groups: Regional
    - Miscellaneous regional groups - correspondence to 1921 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Private Groups: State
    - New York State Agricultural Society 1929 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - New York State Council of Rural Women 1931-1941 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Home Bureau Creed and Home Bureau Song (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Home Bureau - union with Home Economics (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Farm and Home Bureaus: correspondence on problems of individual Bureaus - to 1921 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - New York State Federation of Home Bureaus - 1925-33 (Box 13, Folder 16-20)
    - New York State Federation of Home Bureaus - and the College Marketing Program, 1929 (Box 13, Folder 21-24)
    - Farm and Home Bureau - recommended constitution 1931 (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - New York State Federation of Home Bureaus - 1934-1940 (Box 13, Folder 26-28)
    - New York State Federation of Home Bureaus - correspondence 1940-46 (Box 13, Folder 29-32)
    - New York State Federation of Home Bureau - Reports 1941-1942 (Box 13, Folder 33-37)
    - New York State Federation of Home Bureau Reports 1943-1946 (Box 13, Folder 38-41)
    - Home Bureau Federation Publicity Workshop - September 1950 (Box 13, Folder 42)
    - Farm-Home Bureau - Extension - realignment (Box 13, Folder 43-44)
    - State Federation of Home Bureaus Handbook - 1944-1945 (Box 13, Folder 45)
    - New York State Federation of Presidents of Women's Educational Organizations - 1921-1934 (Box 13, Folder 46-50)
    - Conference Board of Women's Organizations in New York State - 1935-1943 (Box 13, Folder 51-55)
    - New York State Federation of Women's Clubs - correspondence to 1921 (Box 14, Folder 1-3)
    - New York State Federation of Women's Clubs - 1932-1936 (Box 14, Folder 4-5)
    - New York State Home Economics Association (Box 14, Folder 6-8)
    - New York State Home Economics Clubs 1948 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - New York League of Women Voters 1936-1943 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - New York State Social Hygiene Society - correspondence to 1921 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous State Organizations - correspondence to 1921 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Private Groups: Local
    - Ithaca P.T.A. Study Group - 1935-1939 (Box 14, Folder 13-14)
    - Local Library Organizations - correspondence to 1921 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous Local Organizations - correspondence to 1921 (Box 14, Folder 16-17)
    - Visitors to College of Home Economics 1926-1959 (Box 14, Folder 18-21)
  - Educational Groups: Universities and Colleges
    - University of the State of New York, correspondence to 1921 (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - New York State School of Agriculture, (Long Island) correspondence, 1915 (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Other New York State (government supported) Colleges, correspondence to 1921 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Other State Universities, correspondence (Box 14, Folder 25-28)
    - Miscellaneous colleges and universities, A-M, correspondence (Box 14, Folder 29)
    - Miscellaneous colleges and universities, N-Z, correspondence (Box 14, Folder 30)